<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesus Santander</title>
    <description>My personal website and blog</description>
    <link>https://jsantander.me/</link>
    <atom:link href="https://jsantander.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 22:50:57 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2017 22:50:57 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Using GitHub to Create and Host a Personal Website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an opinion note about my switch to using GitHub and Jekyll for this website. My switch largely centered around this rant that played itself out quite frequently in my head:&lt;!--break--&gt;  When you want something simple, having a WordPress site often comes with a lot of other things: a web hosting plan, updating plugins, monitoring auto-updates so your site’s template and functionality don’t break, a MySQL database, dealing with being a target for hackers, a lot of clicking around and fussing with settings, hacking Thesis, and on and on. &lt;!-- flesh the previous sentence out with links --&gt; For a personal website that features just few pages, a CV, and maybe a place to write blog posts and link to your social media accounts and departmental web pages – or just experiment around with the awesomeness of HTML5 &lt;!-- flesh this out with links to codepen stuff or --&gt; and the amazing things you can do with client side scripting &lt;!-- ahem, more links --&gt;, WordPress is bloated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do I really need to make a database call to serve an About page with less than 500 words on it? No. Do I want a bunch of third-party scripts from whatever plugin author(s) just to have social sharing tools? No. Do I want to have to hack PHP in an existing WordPress template to adjust the banner for my logo or to just simplify the user experience? No. I still want to be able to get up and running in less than five minutes, but can’t it be a little lighter?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I made a wishlist of the things I wanted for a personal website:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;special-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Simplicity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Good performance and reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; No databases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Hosting to be free or really cheap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; A custom domain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; The ability to work on my site from anywhere if needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To use open source tools supported by an active development community.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To get up and running quickly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To have version control on my website, preferably Git.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; To be able to share my code so others can easily re-use it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://staticgen.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;There are a lot of lightweight CMS options out there&lt;/a&gt;, but I fell for the GitHub + Jekyll = &lt;i class=&quot;fa fa-heart&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt; toolchain. It&#39;s well known and now pretty established, and the partnership it has developed with Jekyll developers (it&#39;s based in Ruby) and its use of Markdown to separate content from markup just seemed to click with me as a ocassional web developer. It may not be for everybody, but after an afternoon playing around with and getting over the learning curve, I think it can be for a lot more than developers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll has no database! Jekyll runs nothing on the server. It just keeps files ready to be served. Jekyll is really simple once you understand the basic structure and functions. It supports markdown for posts and pages. It uses the famous Liquid Syntax by shopify for conditional logic and other functionalities which actually human readable coding! I think this way of coding is very comprehensive even to a non-coder. So, if you are thinking about to switch, from my experience I advise to you do, never will back use another thing for your personal website.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>https://jsantander.me/blog/2016/using-github-to-create-and-host-a-personal-website/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jsantander.me/blog/2016/using-github-to-create-and-host-a-personal-website/</guid>
        
        <category>github</category>
        
        <category>github-pages</category>
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Discrete and Continuous Convolution, a Brief Animate Review</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The convolution is a mathematical operator which takes two functions &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;f&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt;, &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;g&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and converts them into a third &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;f*g&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;!--break--&gt; that represent the magnitude in which are overlapped: &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;f&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; and an inverted version of &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;g&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember that the first time I heard this, I thought that the concept was a little abstract to understand. But it turns out that in reality it’s not complicated, it’s only necessary to see it in action to understand its meaning. So, why not create a program that makes the convolution between two signals step by step? First, let me introduce the math equations for discrete-time and continuos-time convolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Continuos version is an integral:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\tag{1} f*g=\int^{\infty}_{-\infty} f(\tau)g(t - \tau)d\tau&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And discrete version is a summation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex; mode=display&quot;&gt;\tag{2} f*g=\sum^{\infty}_{m=-\infty} f[m]g[n-m]&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can see the convolution just a fancy word for the operation per se, like a matrix product or even simple, like a polynomials sum. But in this post we are interesting in understand how works this operation. And here we go:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;main_block&quot;&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;inner_block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/convpost/convrect.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Convolution rect&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

 &lt;div class=&quot;inner_block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/convpost/convgaus.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Convolution gaus&quot; /&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The animations above graphically illustrate the convolution of two boxcar functions (left) and two Gaussians (right). In the plots, the green curve shows the convolution of the blue and red curves as a function of &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;t&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; the position indicated by the vertical green line. The gray region indicates the product &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;f(\tau)g(t-\tau)&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; as function of &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;t&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; so its area as a function of &lt;span class=&quot;inlinecode&quot;&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;math/tex&quot;&gt;t&lt;/script&gt;&lt;/span&gt; is precisely the convolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;main_block&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/images/convpost/conv.gif&quot; alt=&quot;convolution&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code for do this animation is in my &lt;a href=&quot;https://gist.github.com/rymnikski/454534def5f037ccc08b59a37d79a7b3&quot;&gt;Github Gist&lt;/a&gt; you can modify and play with it, works with Matlab and Octave, in case that you want view a continuos version, just change ‘stem’ by ‘plot’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;&lt;b&gt;References&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul class=&quot;special-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;small&gt;
&lt;li&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/about/author.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Weisstein, Eric W&lt;/a&gt;. &quot;Convolution.&quot; From &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MathWorld&lt;/a&gt;--A &lt;a href=&quot;http://mathworld.wolfram.com/Convolution.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wolfram Web Resource&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt; Convolution. (n.d.). In Wikipedia. Retrieved November 2013, From &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Convolution&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Wikipedia Resource&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/small&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2013 00:00:00 -0430</pubDate>
        <link>https://jsantander.me/blog/2013/Discrete-and-continuous-convolution-a-brief-interactive-review/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://jsantander.me/blog/2013/Discrete-and-continuous-convolution-a-brief-interactive-review/</guid>
        
        <category>Matlab</category>
        
        <category>Basics-Signals</category>
        
        
        <category>Signal-Processing</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
